

YULIIA (Julia) DOBROVA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / FRONT END DEVELOPER

specializing in JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Node.js



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with a history of over 5 years in application website and development.

Worked on various projects, from developing solo-projects and web applications to contributing to social media platforms and school management systems.

Technical background in Civil Design Engineering holding a Master's degree, offering over 10 years of both executive and management positions.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- REST API
- React
- Redux Toolkit
- Axios
- WebSocket
- Flexbox, Grid
- Parcel, Webpack, Babel
- Preprocessor SASS (SCSS)
- Material-UI
- Bootstrap, jQuery
- Styled-components
- Node.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- NoSQL
- Postman
- Swagger
- JWT (JSON Web token)
- Git
- GitHub
- Vercel, Netlify, Heroku
- Visual Studio Code
- Copilot
- NPM, Yarn
- Responsive/Adaptive design
- Python
- Agile, Scrum
- UI / UX Design Principles
- Figma
- Slack
- PM Tools (Click-Up, Jira)
- AutoCAD

WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO AND PROFILES

https://yuliiadobrova.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yuliia-dobrova/

https://github.com/YuliaDobrova

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer / Software Engineer at Research and Production Enterprise "Ukrradioprom" LLC (April 2023 - Present)

- Designed a user-friendly web application for managing client product databases, specializing in solutions for the rocket-space and aviation fields.
- Implemented an innovative data supervision methodology, resulting in a significant 20% increase in sales within 6 months.

Front End Developer / Software Engineer at Web Tech Company "TensionX" ("SaaS Insiders") (February 2022 - March 2023)

- Contributed to collaborative Git practices with a team of 7 developers and successfully delivered an international social media platform for elder women within a 3-month deadline.
- Developed authorization forms, managed backend data exchange, and implemented real-time comment display using WebSocket technology, leading to a 60% decrease in data processing time.
- Integrated text translation for the entire application and enhanced overall user experience, resulting in a 45% increase in international user engagement.
- Improved user experience and system efficiency in an existing School Management System, digitizing all paperwork related to student marks and success, and introducing specialized analytics interfaces for both parents and teachers, resulting in an 80% increase in the accessibility of student performance data.

Front End Developer / Software Engineer at Dental Center of Dr. Krolyk (November 2021 - January 2022)

- Designed and developed a fully interactive, multilingual website with geolocation features and device adaptability.
- Completed the project within 2 months and successfully deployed it to hosting.

Civil Design Engineer / Head of the Project Department / Front End Software Developer Engineering Company "Avtomagistral" LCC (September 2018 - February 2021)

- As a licensed Civil Design Engineer proficient in AutoCAD, oversaw project approvals and supervised projects during construction. Coordinated 50 projects for new design or reconstruction across various infrastructure sectors within 6 months, leading a diverse team of 30 engineers.
- Implemented a multi-page business card website for our company with the aim of attracting new customers, leading to a 25% growth in our customer base within 3 months.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer Course (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React.js, Node.js) GoIT - International Ed-Tech Company (2021)

Master's Degree in Water Resources Engineering (AutoCAD)

The Faculty of Geography, National University of Kyiv, Ukraine (2009)